BRENDAN CORDOVA

SUMMARY

LEAD FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Passionate Lead Full Stack Software Developer with a focus on problem solving and results. 3 years coding experience and 5 years of computer hardware experience. Leads frontend projects on a variety of languages and frameworks such as TypeScript, React, NextJS, Framer-Motion, Tailwind CSS, and more. Mentors other developers on fundamentals and advanced topics. Dedicated Full Stack Engineer, with multiple years of work experience and contract experience.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Lead Full Stack Developer, 04/2023 - Current **Books Beats Box**

- Manages both Backend and Frontend aspects of development process with a focus on the Frontend.
- Transforms wireframes from Figma into highly responsive, animated, data-driven applications.
- Builds out mobile and desktop applications.
- Collaborates with DevOps team on AWS serverless back-ends.
- Leads in frontend projects in transforming wireframes and ideas into functional, highly user experience focused applications.
- Participates in design (UX/UI) with the design team in Figma.

Software Engineer, 08/2022 - Current Colorado Technical University

- Collaborates with development team on curriculum & learning platform
- Builds out digital tools to roll out to student learning and process optimization
- Develops full-stack applications using MERN and Python/Flask/MySql
- Teaches classes of up to 80 students on modern coding languages, frameworks, and fundamentals
- Conducts hundreds of code review sessions
- Runs coding workshops: Git, GitHub, CSS, React, JavaScript, Python, TypeScript, and Tailwind CSS
- Works on applications that pull in openAI functionality to create and optimize bots

Software Developer, 06/2021 - 05/2023 **Specialist in Probate**

- · Worked to produce wireframes for website
- Developed, updated, maintained, and deployed new additions to company code
- Built internal applications w/ ReactJS

Software Developer, 08/2020 - 05/2023 **Legacy Builds LLC**

 Designed and deployed entire website using MongoDB, Express, React, and NodeJS, and AWS



CONTACT

Address: Silverdale, WA 98383

Phone: 425-802-4573

Email: cordovalegacy19@gmail.com

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

S.M.E. Certification, Subject Matter Expert - MERN/Python/Fundamentals, 01/2023

Colorado Technical University

Certificate of Graduation, Software Development, 09/2022

Coding Dojo

Black Belt Certificate of Completion, MongoDB, Express, React, NodeJS, 07/2022

Coding Dojo

Certificate of Completion, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, 06/2022

Coding Dojo

Certificate of Completion, NextJS- V.13, 05/2023

Udemy

SKILLS

- Languages: React, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, CSS, HTML, JQuery, Ajax
- Frameworks: NextJS, NodeJS, Redux, Tailwind, Express, Flask, Bootstrap,

• Actively managed and maintained company code

PROFESSIONAL PROJECTS

- Portfolio: (https://nextjs13-cordova-portfolio.vercel.app/)
- Search Engine: (https://nextjs13-googleclone.vercel.app/)
- Legacy Builds, LLC: (www.legacybuildspc.com)
- IMDB Clone: (https://imdb-clone-cordovalegacy.vercel.app/)
- Specialist in Probate: (https://glacial-dawn-05023.herokuapp.com/)
- GitHub Projects: (https://github.com/cordovalegacy) 170+ repositories, 900 contributions.

- SASS, Framer Motion, MUI, Vite, GraphQL
- ORM: Mongoose, Prisma, Django
- Databases: MongoDB, MySQL (NoSQL & SQL)
- Tools: Git, Github, Heroku, Vercel, AWS EC2, AWS Lambdas, AWS Microservices, AWS Route-53, VSCode, Postman, Miro, Figma, Jira, Trello